Clayton Siby

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

claytonsiby@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | AngelList | Medium | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Software developer specializing in web application development, maintenance, and implementation of high-quality resolution to disparate systems. Developed a social-media application that gained 10 users within a week. Fluent in multiple languages, frameworks, and technologies, and capable of ramping quickly and efficiently.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, Bootstrap, React-Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL, C#, PostgreSql, SQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Code Reviewing, Giving Constructive Feedback

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS
Full-Stack Web Developer

Remote February 2019 – Present

The Gentleman App — A web-based application that allows users to view man's fashion (suits) and make an appointment to try the ones they are interested in. source-code / view-live. View the Back-End API

- Built with: (ReactJs, JavaScript, Redux, redux-persist, Netlify, Heroku, Ruby on Rails, Ruby)
- Developed the back-end Rails API and implemented the Front-end following a given design.

LifeStyle Articles — Built following business specifications and design, users can share business, fitness, fashion tips through the use of articles. <u>source-code</u> / <u>view-live</u>.

- Built with: (Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Bootstrap, PostgreSQL, RSpec, Cloudinary, Hirb, Heroku)
- Implemented the PostgreSQL Database integration & User Interface using Rails Framework.

Phaser3 Bug Dodger —A browser game in which players are required to dodge the falling bugs to survive.

source-code /view-live.

- Built with: (Phaser3, Webpack, Jest, JavaScript (ES6), CSS)
- Developed the UI & UX using the Phaser3 library & ES6 syntax including classes and modules for code readability and maintenance.

FREELANCE SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Remote

Full-Stack Developer

February 2019 - Present

- Developed an e-commerce website for a client and integrating the payment method plugins.
- Developed a shopping cart web page implementing the UI and the payment methods integrations.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE

March 2020 - April 2021

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

FREECODECAMP

Certificate, Algorithms and Data Structures

January 2019 – November 2019

- Spent 300+ hours mastering algorithms and data structures in JavaScript.
- Mastered communication skills through the developer interactive forum provided by the FreeCodeCamp.